Finding Aid for the Stanley Chase Papers LSC.1090
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Television, 1925-1994.; 32 boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 map folder.
  - Subseries 3C: Miscellaneous productions, 1925-1994.; 13.5 boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 map folder.
    - Columbia Pictures and Screen Gems program reports., 1963. (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Screen Gems Project status reports., 1963-1964. (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Screen Gems rejection letters., 1964. (Box 140, Folder 3)
      Letters from Chase rejecting show and script ideas.
    - Screen Gems correspondence., 1962-1963. (Box 140, Folder 4-5)
    - ABC development materials., 1963-1964. (Box 140, Folder 6)
      Credits, clippings, financial documents.
    - Feature film reports., 1962-1963. (Box 140, Folder 7)
      From ABC, Universal, Paramount, Columbia studios.
    - Assorted contracts and correspondence., 1963.; [2 folders]. (Box 140, Folder 8, Box 141)
      From ABC.
    - Screen Gems memoranda., 1963-1964.; [4 folders]. (Box 141, Folder 2-4, Box 142)
    - Writer credits., 1958-1963. (Box 141, Folder 5-6)
    - Producers and directors., 1963-1964. (Box 141, Folder 7)
      Assorted print material.
    - Casting file--Screen Gems., 1962-1964. (Box 141, Folder 8-9)
    - Correspondence., 1963-1964. (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous productions., 1952-1967. (Box 142, Folder 2-3)
      Assorted print materials, primarily related to Universal City Studios and the Chrysler Theatre.
    - Universal correspondence., 1965-1968. (Box 142, Folder 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous productions., 1952-1967. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Various shooting schedules and credits., 1966-1967. (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Universal City Studios miscellaneous files., 1961-1967. (Box 143, Folder 3-6)
    - Alien Dust., 1970-1974. (Box 143, Folder 7-8)
    - Time of Flight preliminary production design drawing. Artist unknown. 2 images of nude man and transport chamber., 1966. (Box 93)
      Acrylic on paper, mounted on board. Measures approx. 19'' x 30.5.'' Chrysler Theatre production.
  - Subseries 3D: Scripts, 1960-1984.; 19 boxes.
    This subseries consists of assorted scripts and story pitches.
    - Chrysler Theatre story submissions--36, 92, and 96., 1966-1967. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Chrysler Theatre story submissions--100-119., 1966-1967. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Chrysler Theatre story submissions--120-129., 1966-1967. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Chrysler Theatre story submissions--130-139., 1966-1967. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Chrysler Theatre story submissions--140-169., 1966-1967. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Tokatyan, Leon. The Posse., 1966 March. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Wood, William. A Song Called Revenge., 1966 June- August. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - McBain, Ed and Stanford Whitmore. Deadlock., 1967 March. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Sitowitz, Hal. The Day of the Gun., 1966 April 26. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Pogostin, S. Lee. Crazier Than Cotton., 1966 February - March. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Zweiback, A. Martin. All the Money in the World-- Who Needs It?!, no date. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Matheson, Richard. Time of Flight., 1966 June- July. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Michaels, Sidney. Live, Love, Laugh, and Be Happy., 1966 August. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Ellis, David. Verdict for Terror., 1967 January. (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Welles, Halsted. The Lady is My Wife., 1966 September - Decemeber. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Brooks, Mel. The Zero Mostel Show., 1963 October 20. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Pilot. Screen Gems, INC.
    - Playdon, Paul. War of the Worlds., 1973 November 7. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Writer's work draft for pre-production. Paramount Television.
    - Matheson, Richard. Race Against Time., 1966. (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Pilot no. 81084 for Stanley Chase, producer, and Universal Television. Presentation piece included.
    - MacDonald, John and Richary Murphy. Venture Bay., no date. (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Concept and pilot treatment for series television. George Litto / Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Twain, Norman. Two by Willingham., no date. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Gay, John. Wyatt Smith., 1982 March 10. (Box 37, Folder 6)
      Twentieth Century Fox Television.
    - Brody, Larry. Kyrell B.R.T., 1973. (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Script and pilot presentation.
    - The Knights of the Circus., no date. (Box 37, Folder 8)
      Columbia Pictures Television synopsis.
    - Pettus, Ken. Dateline: Paradise., no date. (Box 37, Folder 9)
      Television series. Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Gillis, Jackson. Sidewinder., no date. (Box 37, Folder 10)
      "Friday Night Football" episode. Television series. Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Mandelberg, Cynthia. The Grace Kelly Story., 1982. (Box 37, Folder 11)
      Embassy Television.
    - Chase, Stanley and S.S. Schweitzer. Rescue., no date. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Chase, Stanley and Bob Kaufman. Happily Ever After., 1964 December 28. (Box 38, Folder 2)
      Half-hour comedy series with Chase as executive producer. Stanley Chase Productions and Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer INC.
    - Malko, George. Kavik the Wolf Dog., no date. (Box 38, Folder 3)
      Based on the novel by Walt Morey. Pantheon Television.
    - Chase, Stanley and Mark Fink. Marriage for a Living., no date. (Box 38, Folder 4)
      Comedy series. Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Chase, Stanley and William O. Turner. Five Days to Salt Lake., no date. (Box 38, Folder 5)
      Television series based on the novel by William O. Turner. Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Matheson, Richard. Vandaih., no date. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Chase, Stanley and Gary Belkin. 2084., no date. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Chase, Stanley. Johnny Hunter., no date. (Box 38, Folder 8)
      Synopsis for a Western series.
    - Knopf, Christopher. Red River., 1976 January 19. (Box 38, Folder 9)
      Pilot for television series. Chase/Rearguard Productions.
    - Capp, Al. Fearless Fosdick., 1984 December 4. (Box 38, Folder 10)
      "The Little Shrinker" teleplay.
    - Kleiner, Harry. Jigsaw., 1965 October 23. (Box 38, Folder 11)
      Pilot Script no. 83301-1. Universal City Studios and Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Pettus, Ken and Tim Maschler. Donovan's Choice., no date. (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Television series synopsis. Stanley Chase Productions.
    - Schweitzer, S.S. Norton's Rounds., no date. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Slade, Bernard. The Girl with Something Extra., 1972. (Box 38, Folder 14)
      Comedy series for television, pilot episode no. 183049, "Sally on my Mind."
    - Chase, Stanley and Bob Kaufman. Dream Wife., 1964. (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Comedy series for television. Stanley Chase, executive producer. Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, INC.
    - Chase, Stanley and Brad Schreiber. Make a Wish., no date. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Huver, Scott and Stanley Chase. The Golden Triangle of Beverly Hills., no date. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Huver, Scott and Stanley Chase. The Dream Factory., no date. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Dresner, Hall and Joe Goldberg. The Silver Platter., no date. (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Television play outline.
    - Fisher, Bob and Arthur Alsberg. September Jones., 1962. (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Pilot script. Selmur Productions, INC.
    - Chase, Stanley and Terry Ryan. Stop, You're Killing Me!, no date. (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Television comedy.
    - Michaels, Sidney. The Affair., 1966 December. (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Includes synopsis for TV adaptation and a laudatory letter to Chase from Michaels.
    - Russell, A.J. Vidocq:, 1966 August 8. (Box 39, Folder 9)
      No. 81079. Pilot episode, "Murder in a Leaning Skyscraper," and "Death Comes for the Triptych." Universal City Studios.
    - Barkan, Mark and Ellen M. Gameral. Why Not?, no date. (Box 39, Folder 10)
      Presentation synopsis of a television comedy series.
    - Sabaroff, Robert. The Virginian., 1965-1966. (Box 39, Folder 11)
      "One Spring Like Long Ago" episode.
    - Gethers, Steven. That's Where the Money Is., 1967. (Box 39, Folder 12)
      Stanley Chase, producer. Universal Television.
    - Arnold, Danny. Bewitched., 1964. (Box 39, Folder 13)
      Prospectus and episodes no. 3915, "Mother Meet's What's-His-Name!!" and no. 3905, "It Shouldn't Happen to a Dog" (written by Jerry Davis).
    - Sowards, Jack. Cannon., 1968. (Box 39, Folder 14)
      Produced by Ron Roth. Universal City Studios.
    - Sanford, Donald. Catch a Nightmare by the Tail., 1965 November. (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Universal Studios.
    - Petrakis, Henry Mark and Sam Peckinpah. The Dick Powell Show., 1962 July 31. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Episode no. 5137, "Pericles on 31st Street." Produced by Sam Peckinpah. Four Star Television.
    - Perl, Arnold. The Hard Edge., 1965 September 2. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      Pilot script. Universal City Studios.
    - Sabaroff, Robert. The Invaders., 1967 July 3. (Box 40, Folder 4)
      First draft of "Valley of the Shadow" episode. QM Productions.
    - Ellis, David. Trials of O'Brien., no date. (Box 40, Folder 5)
      "No Justice for the Judge" episode, production no. 11.
    - Chase, Stanley and Richard Matheson. Nightmare Alley., no date. (Box 40, Folder 6)
      Television series synopsis. Includes contract agreements.
    - Chase, Stanley and Ben Maddow. Mr. X., no date. (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Television series synopsis.
    - Brooks, Mel. Inside Danny Baker., 1962. (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Pilot and revision. United Artist's Television.
    - Box, Edgar. The Perfect Crime., no date. (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Pilot script.
    - Westwind., no date. (Box 40, Folder 10)
      Proposal for a five-episode television series. Screen Gems and Corday Productions, INC.
    - Auster, Islin. Gideon Knight., no date. (Box 40, Folder 11)
      Proposal based on The Count of Monte Cristo.
    - Kaminsky, Howard and Charles Sopkin. Cheers for Lacy., no date. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Comedy television series proposal and script.
    - Peyton Place., 1963 June 4. (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Scripts for episodes 1-6. Paul Monash, executive producer.
    - Carothers, A.J. The Card and the Badge., no date. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Pilot script for episode one, "Murder, London -- New York." Based on the novel by John Creasey. Screen Gems.
    - Knopf, Christopher. Maryk., 1964 September 1. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Screen Gems, INC.
    - Kleiner, Harry. The Three., no date. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Treatment for a television series.
    - Friedberg, Billy. Old Man Webster., no date. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Naked City., no date. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Screen Gems, INC. story lines for 66 half-hour shows.
    - Allen, Woody. The Laughmakers., 1962. (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Edgewater Production in association with the American Broadcasting Company; created and produced by Robert Alan Aurthur.
    - Simms, Jay. The Conover Cons., no date. (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Television series idea.
    - Arnold, Jay. Hi Neighbor., no date. (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Kaufman, Bob and Peter Barry. The Great Chase., 1964 July 7. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Webster, Tony., no date. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Pilot draft for United Artists TV.
    - Chase, Stanley and Terry Ryan. Coffin's Museum., no date. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Comedy-terror series for television.
    - Kohner, Frederick. Gidget., 1960. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Sneider, Vern. Northwest Command, The Tactician, and Frenchtown Midnight., no date. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Typed manuscript television series proposals.
    - Morning Star., no date. (Box 42, Folder 6)
      Television serial proposal. Corday Productions, INC.
    - Chase, Stanley. The Russian., no date. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Phillips, Irna, et. al. Days of our Lives., no date. (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Proposal. Corday Productions, INC.
    - Brooks, Mel and Buck Henry. Get Smart!, no date. (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Talent Associates-Paramount Limited.
    - Bezzerides, A.I. The Big Valley., no date. (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Prospectus for a television series.
    - Universal City Studios., 1967-1968. (Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50)
      Story department submissions
- Series 4: Audiovisual materials, 1959-1989.; 1 box, 2 oversize boxes.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file levels. All requests to access processed audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  This series consists of sound recordings and two videos. The bulk of the recordings are from Free and Easy, a Harold Arlen and Johnny Mercer jazz musical featuring Quincy Jones. Other materials include The Threepenny Opera cast production recordings and Mack the Knife soundtracks on compact disc, audiocassette, and vinyl LP. (Note: Film materials were transferred to the UCLA Film and Television Archive in September 2005; see Special Collections reference desk for more information.)
  - Mack the Knife, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
    Two sealed vinyl LPs, two compact discs, and two audiocassettes of the original soundtrack.
  - Free and Easy, 1959 November 12; yrlsc_1090_60_02_001; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:23:39) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Scope and Contents
    Transcribed from container: "Stanley Chase Productions #134162 11/12/59" Content note: non-musical sound score
  - Free and Easy Tape 2, 1959; yrlsc_1090_60_02_002; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:05:32) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    Content note: non-musical sound score
  - Free and Easy Tape 3, 1959 November 11; yrlsc_1090_60_02_003; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:24:17) (Box 60, Folder 2)
    Transcribed from container: "Stanley Chase Productions #134162 11/11/59" Content note: non-musical sound score
  - Free and Easy Paris Performance- 1A, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_01_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:22) (Box 144, Folder 1)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy Paris Performance Quincy Jones Jazz band and cast. 1A"
  - Free and Easy Paris Performance- 1B, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_01_02; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:23:00) (Box 144, Folder 1)
    Transcribed from container: "1B"
  - Free and Easy Paris Performance- 2A, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_01_03; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:21:24) (Box 144, Folder 1)
    Transcribed from container: "2A"
  - Free and Easy Paris Performance- 2B, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_01_04; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:14:47) (Box 144, Folder 1)
    Transcribed from container: "2B"
  - Free and Easy Paris Performance- 2C, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_02_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:03:37) (Box 144, Folder 2)
    Transcribed from container exterior: "2C?" Transcribed from container interior: "?A Free and Easy?"
  - Free and Easy Paris Perfromance- 3B, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_02_02; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:27:15) (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - ThreePenny Opera Part I, undated; yrlsc_1090_144_03_01a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:45) (Box 144, Folder 3)
    Content Note: Recording is from "Three Penny Opera", but container describes materials as "Free and Easy Effect Tracks."
  - ThreePenny Opera Part II, undated; yrlsc_1090_144_03_01b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:10) (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - ThreePenny Opera Part I, undated; yrlsc_1090_144_03_02a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:27:03) (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - ThreePenny Opera Part II, undated; yrlsc_1090_144_03_02b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:21) (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Free and Easy--Effect Tracks, 1959 November 12; yrlsc_1090_144_03_03; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:20:10) (Box 144, Folder 3)
    Transcribed from container: " #134162 Sec Copy Effects Free and Easy"
  - Free and Easy--Effect Tracks, 1959 November 12; yrlsc_1090_144_03_04; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:11:40) (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Free and Easy-- Harold Arlen Performances 1, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_04_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:30:55) (Box 144, Folder 4)
    Transcribed from container: "Tape 1- Side 1 'Free and Easy'; Harold Arlen (+ others) playing at piano and singing his own material for the show"
  - Free and Easy-- Harold Arlen Performances 2, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_04_02; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:31:14) (Box 144, Folder 4)
    Transcribed from container: "Tape 2- Side 2 'Free and Easy'; Harold Arlen (continued) (+ others) playing at piano and singing his own material for the show"
  - Free and Easy-- Harold Arlen Performances 3, 1959-1960; yrlsc_1090_144_04_03; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:33) (Box 144, Folder 4)
    Transcribed from container: "End of 2 and 3 'Free and Easy'; Harold Arlen (continued) (+ others) playing at piano and singing his own material for the show"
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_01a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:32:33) (Box 144, Folder 5)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy Straight Dub; Prop. Stan Chase"
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_01b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:48:03) (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_02a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:47:28) (Box 144, Folder 5)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy Straight Dub (No EQ). Prop. Stan Chase"
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_02b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:45:22) (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_03; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:08:45) (Box 144, Folder 5)
    Transcribed from reel: "Free and Easy Tape 3"
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, 1959; yrlsc_1090_144_05_04; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:02:15) (Box 144, Folder 5)
    Transcribed from reel: "Free and Easy Tape 1" Transcribed from container: "Porgy and Bess"
  - Free and Easy--Miscellaneous Recordings, undated; yrlsc_1090_144_06_01; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:03:27) (Box 144, Folder 6)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy; Prop. Stan Chase"
  - Free and Easy- Harold Arlen Performance Part 1, 1960 July 2; yrlsc_1090_144_07_01a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:00) (Box 144, Folder 7)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy. Orchestra- Harold Arlen. First Part and End. Alhambra. Sunday Matineé."
  - Free and Easy- Harold Arlen Performance Part 1, 1960 July 2; yrlsc_1090_144_07_01a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:55:10) (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Free and Easy- Harold Arlen Performance Part 2, 1960 July 2; yrlsc_1090_144_07_02a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:37:58) (Box 144, Folder 7)
    Transcribed from container: "Free and Easy. Ochestra- Harold Arlen. Second Part. Alhambra. Sunday Matineé"
  - Free and Easy- Harold Arlen Performance Part 2, 1960 July 2; yrlsc_1090_144_07_02b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:35:55) (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Videos, circa 1970-1974 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    Video includes a piece by John Henry Faulk, writer and inspiration for Fear on Trial, and an interview with Stanley Chase on Fuji Beta L-125 from the Dr. Morton Cooper television show.
    - Stanley Chase Interviewed on "Change Your Voice Change Your Life" with Dr. Morton Cooper, 1985; yrlsc_1090_145_01_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; communiCom; 1 Video Recordings (1 Betamax; Duration: 0:29:55) (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Happy End Audio Reel #1, 1972; yrlsc_1090_145_02_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:18:46) (Box 145, Folder 2)
    Transcribed from container: "Property of Stanley Chase Productions; Brecht-Weill Happy End Side 1 Reel #1; Lotte Lenya"
  - Happy End Audio Reel #1, 1972; yrlsc_1090_145_02_02; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:18:49) (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Happy End Audio Reel #2, 1972; yrlsc_1090_145_02_03; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:20:06) (Box 145, Folder 2)
    Transcribed from container: "Property of Stanley Chase Productions; Brecht-Weill Happy End Side 2 Reel #2; Lotte Lenya"
  - Happy End Audio Reel #2, 1972; yrlsc_1090_145_02_04; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:20:02) (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Dreams of Alvin audio reel, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_03_01; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:16:33) (Box 145, Folder 3)
    Transcribed from container: "Dreams of Alvin TV Series; Mel Brooks and Stanley Chase" Content Note: Mel Brooks and Stanley Chase explain their idea for a new tv series
  - Stanley Chase on Dame Sybil Thorndike, CBC Radio, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_04_01; communiCom; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:12:22) (Box 145, Folder 4)
    Transcribed from container: "Stanly Chase re Dame Sybil Thorndike CBC Radio Laurier Lapierre
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_01a; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:27:03) (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_01b; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:10) (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_02a; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:27:16) (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_02b; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:26:22) (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_03a; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:27:22) (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - The Three Penny Opera, undated; yrlsc_1090_145_05_03b; Chase, Stanley, 1927-2014; 1 Sound Recordings (1 audiocassette; Duration: 0:26:39) (Box 145, Folder 5)
- Series 5: Miscellaneous, 1944.; 1 folder, 1 map folder.
  This collection consists of Stanley Chase's high school year book from 1944, and a Jacques Eitel watercolor entitled "Avec mon bon souvenir," signed in pencil by the artist.
  - New Utrecht High School yearbook., 1944. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    New Utrecht High's "The Comet," New York. Chase was then known as Stanley Cohen.
  - Jacques Eitel watercolor. "Avec mon bon souvenir.", no date. (Box 92)
    Limited series (9/50), signed in pencil.